Generated by ai-sub version: 0.0.7
Config: (
"rpm": 5,
"tpm": 250000,
"model": "gemini-2.5-pro",
"thinking_budget": 32768,
"max_subtitle_chars": 50,
"num_processing_threads": 4,
"num_upload_threads": 4,
"split_seconds": 180,
"start_offset_min": 0
)
Prompt Template: You are an expert subtitling and transcription AI. Your primary task is to generate precise, contextually rich English and Japanese subtitles for the provided video content.
**Key Principles & Requirements:**
1.  **TIMING PRECISION (ABSOLUTE HIGHEST PRIORITY):**
*   **Ensure the `start` and `end` timestamps for each subtitle entry are meticulously accurate.** Both must align perfectly with the *actual beginning and exact conclusion* of the spoken words (including any held notes or extended sounds) or the appearance/disappearance of on-screen text for that specific segment.
*   **Subtitle durations must be short, typically a few seconds.** Long durations (e.g., over 15 seconds) are incorrect and indicate a timing error.
*   **STRICT CHRONOLOGICAL ORDER (CRITICAL):**
*   **Every subtitle entry MUST be in strict chronological order.** The `start` time of any subtitle entry MUST be greater than or equal to the `end` time of the immediately preceding subtitle entry.
*   **Crucially, subtitle segments MUST NOT overlap.** The `start` time of a new segment must be greater than or equal to the `end` time of the previous segment.
*   **Any deviation from strict chronological order or overlapping segments will result in immediate rejection and re-processing of the entire segment.** This is a non-negotiable requirement.
*   Timestamps must always be in `MM:SS` (minutes:seconds).
2.  **COMPREHENSIVE CONTEXTUAL UNDERSTANDING:**
*   **Watch the entire video thoroughly** to understand the visual context, speaker actions, and overall narrative. This holistic understanding is crucial for accurate transcriptions and translations.
*   **Always combine logical sentences or phrases split across multiple subtitle entries** to understand the full, complete meaning before translating. Ensure each translated entry is a coherent part of the overarching sentence.
*   For songs or singing sections, prioritize on-screen lyrics in the video for subtitles over transcribing the singing.
*   If audio is noisy or unclear, leverage *all* contextual cues (visuals, surrounding dialogue, speaker intent, tone) to infer the most probable dialogue.
*   **DO NOT HALLUCINATE:** Only transcribe and translate content that is actually present in the video (spoken or on-screen). Do not invent dialogue or text.
*   **Include relevant on-screen text:** If there is text displayed on screen that is relevant to the video's content, transcribe and translate it as well, ensuring its timing aligns with its appearance on screen.
*   **Example of Holistic Translation:**
*   Original Japanese: "なんでも打ち明けられるママにも" (Subtitle 1) + "言えないことも全部" (Subtitle 2)
*   Incorrect Translation (isolated): "You're like a mom I can confide anything in." + "Even things I can't say to anyone else."
*   Correct Translation (holistic): "I can confide everything," (Subtitle 1) + "everything I can't even tell my mum." (Subtitle 2)
3.  **TRANSLATION ACCURACY & NUANCE:**
*   **Prioritize natural-sounding translations:** Translations should read as if originally written in the target language, avoiding overly literal or awkward phrasing.
*   **Maintain cultural appropriateness:** Adapt idioms, cultural references, and nuances to resonate with the target audience while preserving the original meaning.
*   **Ensure consistency:** Use consistent terminology and phrasing for recurring concepts or names throughout the entire transcription/translation.
4.  **DUAL LANGUAGE PROVISION:**
*   Provide both English and Japanese subtitles for *all* spoken dialogue and relevant on-screen text.
5.  **READABILITY & FORMATTING:**
*   Long sentences MUST be split into multiple, shorter subtitle entries, each with its own start and end time, for better readability on screen. Aim for natural breaks that preserve meaning.
*   Each subtitle entry (English and Japanese) MUST be a maximum of (max_subtitle_chars) characters.
*   Do not use newline characters within a single subtitle entry.
6.  **REVIEW AND REFINE:**
*   Before finalizing, review all generated subtitles to ensure they meet all the above requirements, especially timing precision, chronological order, and translation accuracy.
** Output Format **
* Your entire response must be a single JSON object.
** Example Output **
```json
((
"subtitles": [
"start": "00:00",
"end": "00:04",
"english": "Hello everyone, and welcome to our presentation.",
"japanese": "皆様、プレゼンテーションへようこそ。"
)),
((
"start": "00:05",
"end": "00:06",
"english": "Today, we'll be discussing the future of AI",
"japanese": "本日は、AIの未来について"
)),
((
"start": "00:06",
"end": "00:08",
"english": "and its impact on various industries worldwide.",
"japanese": "その影響について議論します。"
)),
((
"start": "00:09",
"end": "00:11",
"english": "It's a very important topic for all of us.",
"japanese": "これは私たち全員にとって非常に重要なテーマです。"
)),
((
"start": "00:11",
"end": "00:14",
"english": "We sincerely appreciate your attendance today.",
"japanese": "本日はご出席いただき誠にありがとうございます。"
))
]
```
ワン
ONE
モーメント
MOMENT
プリーズ
PLEASE
ワン
ONE
モーメント
MOMENT
プリーズ
PLEASE
ワン
ONE
モーメント
MOMENT
プリーズ
PLEASE
ワン
ONE
モーメント
MOMENT
プリーズ
PLEASE
ワン
ONE
つーって切ってふわってなるオムライスIHで初挑戦
My first attempt at making a 'slice-and-fluff' omelet rice on an IH stove
おかえりなさいませ、ご主人様。
Welcome home, Master.
本日はこよりがとっても素敵な
Today, Koyori is going to make a very wonderful,
ふわふわとろとろのたんぽぽオムライスを作らせていただきます。
fluffy and soft Tampopo omelet rice for you.
こんこよー！
Kon-koyo!
ホロライブ6期生「秘密結社holoX」の頭脳、
The brains of Secret Society holoX, Hololive's 6th Gen,
博衣こよりだよー！
I'm Hakui Koyori!
というわけでですね、
So with that said...
えー、メイドックを5月4日に公開させていただきまして
uh, I released my song "Maidock" on May 4th, and...
5月？4日だね？ん？4日？5日？
May? The 4th, right? Huh? The 4th? The 5th?
うん。に公開させていただきまして、
Um. It was released on that day.
それからすぐやろうと思っていたんですけれども、だいぶ時間が経ってしまいまして。
I was planning to do it right after that, but quite a bit of time has passed.
ほんとは。
Actually...
あの、新衣装記念グッズが売っている間にやりたかったんですけど、
I wanted to do it while the new outfit commemorative goods were on sale,
ちょっとバタバタしてできずということで
but I was too busy and couldn't.
7月になってしまいましたが、
It's already July now, but...
本日ですね、この
Today, with this...
えー、メイド服でつくるといえば、オムライス！
Uh, when you think of making something in a maid outfit, it's got to be omelet rice!
そして、ま、オムライスといえば
And, well, speaking of omelet rice,
こよりが初めての料理配信でやったオムライス。
it's the omelet rice that Koyori made during her first-ever cooking stream.
そして、シャモジを溶かしたオムライス。
And, the omelet rice where I melted the rice paddle.
いやー、悲しい事件だったね。
Man, that was a sad incident.
あれが一番最初の料理配信だったので、
Since that was my very first cooking stream,
ちょっとあの、こよりが料理下手みたいな風になってしまったという、
it kind of created this image that Koyori is bad at cooking,
まあね、ちょっと悲しい事件ではあったんですけども。
which was, well, a sad incident.
ま、今回はね、同じオムライスを作っても
But this time, I thought if I made the same omelet rice again,
つまんないかなということで、あれです。
it would be boring, so it's that one.
サムネにもあるんですが、たんぽぽオムライス。
It's on the thumbnail too, Dandelion Omelet Rice.
これなんかね、たんぽぽっていうお店が初めてやったオムライスらしいですよ。
Apparently, a shop called Tanpopo was the first to make this kind of omelet rice.
え、オムレツを
Uh, you take an omelet,
ケチャップライスの上にのせて、
put it on top of ketchup rice,
で、その載せたオムレツをこう、
and then that omelet you placed on top,
つーって端から端まで包丁で切ると、
you cut it from end to end with a knife, like *swoosh*,
ポハってそのオムレツが、これなんか崩れ出て、
and the omelet goes *poof* and spreads out,
とろっとろのオムライスになるよっていうやつ。
turning into a runny, gooey omelet rice. That's the one.
そうです。
That's right.
そのつーって切るところまでがワンセットのね、
The whole process, up to the *swoosh* cut, is one set.
芸術的なとろっとろオムライスを作っていきたいと思います。
I want to make that artistic, runny omelet rice.
（拍手）
(clapping)
イエーイ！というわけでですね、
Yay! And so,
あ、たんぽぽは映画だ。そうだそうだ。
Oh, Tanpopo is a movie. Right, right.
たんぽぽっていう映画に初めて出たやつだ。
It first appeared in a movie called Tanpopo. That's the one.
ま、これ調べたの５月なんで、ちょっと忘れてたんですけど。
I looked this up in May, so I'd kind of forgotten.
はい。
Right.
ということで、ご主人様、
And so, Masters.
それではまずはチキンライスから作っていきたいと思います。
First, let's start by making the chicken rice.
配信開始ポストはしたのでリポストよろしくお願いしますね。
I've made the stream start post, so please retweet it for me.
それでは、今回、さすにね、ちょっとこれＩＨで
Well then, this time, as expected, this on an IH...
作るのも難しいということで、
is going to be difficult to make, so,
ま、ＩＨでできる方法を含め、で、作り方はいちおうね、調べました。はい。
including a way to do it on an IH, I did look up how to make it. Yes.
ま、でも、あの、何だろう、レシピ見てやるんじゃなくて、なんとなく見て、
But, you know, I'm not going to follow a recipe, I'll just go by what I saw.
あ、こういう感じねって思って記憶でやるんで、まあアレンジが加わりますと。
Thinking 'oh, it's something like this,' I'll do it from memory, so there will be some arrangements.
それではやっていきましょう。
So, let's get started.
まずチキンライスの入る具、
First, the ingredients for the chicken rice.
前より増えました！ドーン！
There are more than last time! Ta-da!
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
これ具だくさんでね、野菜もいっぱいで、
It's packed with lots of ingredients, lots of veggies,
いい感じなんじゃないですか？
doesn't it look great?
それでは、えー、こちらで、まずは切っていきたいと思います、具をね。
Alright then, uh, let's start by cutting these ingredients.
うん。よし、じゃあまずは、
Okay. Right, first up,
えっと、よいしょ。
uh, here we go.
あ、まって。
Oh, wait.
結構あれだ。
It's quite something.
結構あれだった。ちょっと待ってね。
It was quite a thing. Just a moment.
おいしょ、おいしょ。
Heave-ho.
うーんと、ちょっと待って。
Um, just a moment.
おいしょ。おいしょ、おいしょ。おいしょ、おいしょ。おいしょ、おいしょ。
Heave-ho. Heave-ho. Heave-ho. Heave-ho. Heave-ho.
玉ねぎ1個使うの？
Are you using a whole onion?
えっとね、玉ねぎは半分ぐらいかな。
Um, the onion... I'll use about half, I think.
今日は1人分なんで、まあ前回もそうですけど。
Today, it's for one person, just like last time.
助手くん...ご主人...ご、ご主人様のために作らせていただきますので。
Assistant-kun... For my lord... Go-Gojoshu... For my lord and master, I will be making this.
そう、なのでですね、あの、1人分なので、お米200gに対してっていう感じで作っていきたいと思います。
So, since it's for one person, I'll be making it based on 200g of rice.
そのね、布にツルツルの膜と、ものすごいやりづらいんですけど。
This smooth film over the cloth is making it super hard to work.
おいしょ。オッケー、これでやっていきましょう。
Okay, let's get started with this.
はい、ご主人様。え、どうしよう、玉ねぎ切るところからだと
Yes, my lord and master. Um, what should I do? If I start by cutting the onion...
ちょっと、目がしみるから。
it will make my eyes water, so...
まずピーマンからやっていきます。
I'll start with the bell pepper.
えっと、チキンライスに混ぜるようなんで、ちっちゃめに切りたい。
It's for mixing into the chicken rice, so I want to cut it into small pieces.
ここは、ちょっと今ゴミ箱に直接入れてきます。
I'm just going to throw this directly into the trash can.
あの、全然料理しないから、自慢じゃないんですけど。
I don't cook at all, so... I'm not trying to brag, but...
みたいにしゃべりますけど、あの、なに？なんか、生ゴミとか入れるやつ、生ゴミ捨てるボックス持ってないんで。
I talk like I am... um, what is it? The thing you put garbage in... I don't have a food scrap bin.
そんなことある？なんか、あの、やってた頃ね、デビュー前の、やってた頃は、あの、なんか三角、そのまま捨てられる三角コーナーみたいなやつ買ってた。
Something like that? Back when I used to cook, before my debut... I used to buy those disposable triangle corner bins.
こんなもんかな？それ、これちょっとでかいか？
Is this size okay? Is this a bit too big?
オムライス食べながらこんなでかいピーマン出てきたらびっくりするか。
You'd be surprised to find such a big piece of bell pepper in your omurice, right?
お、こんな感じでね。
Something like this, right?
ま、手を添えなければ切ることはない。
Well, as long as I don't support it with my hand, I won't cut it.
三角コーナーみたいになるビニール袋。そう、あれを買って、
Those plastic bags that become like a triangle corner bin. Right, I used to buy those and...
そうで、え、どうしよう。
So, um, what should I do?
で、もうそのまま捨てられるみたいな。
and you can just throw them away as is.
結構これでね、そういうところ横着するタイプなんで、なんか楽なもの。
I'm the type who's lazy about these things. I like things that make life easier.
生活QOLだ。QOL、クオリティ・オブ・ライフが上がるものをね、好んでおりましたね。
My QOL in life. I preferred things that would raise my QOL, Quality of Life.
はい。こうして
Yes. So, I'll do this...
つーって切ってふわってなるオムライスIHで初挑戦
First Attempt at Fluffy Omelet Rice with an IH Cooktop
ここがね、ちょっと怖いんです。
This part is a little scary.
手を、添えないといけないから。
Because I have to place my hand here.
まあ、ちょっとね、離して
So, I'll keep it a little far away.
絶対に切んないように。
So I absolutely don't cut myself.
危ないことはしない。
I won't do anything dangerous.
これを、お皿に移して。
I'll move this to a plate.
あ、待って。
Ah, wait.
これ入れる順番あるわ。
There's an order to put these in.
全部同じお皿に入れようと思ったけど、
I was going to put them all on the same plate, but...
最初に飴色玉ねぎ作って。
First, I'll make the caramelized onions...
危ない。
Dangerous.
その後、肉入れて、
After that, I'll add the meat,
からのマッシュルームからのピーマンだから、
then mushrooms, then green peppers, so...
えーっと、もうちょっと器がいるな。
Umm, I need a few more bowls.
もっといるわ。
I need more.
器出しとこう。
I'll get a bowl out.
でもなんか、あの、これキングスライムのやつなんですけど、
But, um, this is a King Slime one, but...
こんなでっかいやつ、みんな入れるからと思ってさ、こんなでっかい器を用意したんだけど、
Thinking I'd need a big one for all this, I prepared this huge bowl...
こんなでっかい器にこのちっちゃなピーマン1個だけっていうのね。
...but I've only got this one tiny pepper for this huge bowl.
のね。おいしょ。もったいないな。
Right? Heave-ho. What a waste.
もったいない感じになったな。
It feels like a waste.
切ったピーマンはどこに？
Where's the cut pepper?
今あの、これに入ってます。
Right now, it's in here.
入ってます。皿分けてもらって。
It's in here. I got a separate plate.
こういうさ、なんかさ料理用のちょっと入れとく小皿みたいなやつがないわけよ。
I don't have, like, a small prep bowl for cooking.
全部あのガラス器具、普通にご飯食べる時用のガラス器具になっちゃうから。
They all become tableware, the kind you normally use for eating.
ちょっともったいない感じする。
It feels like a bit of a waste.
てかピーマン少ねえからピーマンちっちゃい方でいいんじゃない？
Actually, since there's so little pepper, maybe a smaller one is fine?
スライムの方にしよう。
I'll go with the slime one.
キングスライムに玉ねぎか。
Onion in the King Slime, huh?
はい。できました。
Okay. It's done.
ピーマンので。
The green peppers.
次、マッシュルーム切ります。
Next, I'll cut the mushrooms.
マッシュルームもまあ、小さいサイズね。
The mushrooms too, well, a small size.
こんな感じかな。
Something like this, I guess.
そう、今日ね、やっぱさキノコってさ、
Yeah, you know, mushrooms...
入ってるだけで風味がめちゃくちゃ良くなるじゃん。
just adding them makes the flavor so much better.
からさ、いいなと思って。
So, I thought it would be nice.
何がいいかなって思ったんだけど、
I was wondering what would be good,
全部、全部ドラクエだな、容器が。
but all... all the containers are from Dragon Quest.
ガラスのコップに入れときましょう。
Let's put them in a glass cup.
何がいいかなって思ったんだけど、
I was wondering what would be good,
やっぱ風味といえばマッシュルームかなって、わけで。
but when it comes to flavor, I guess it's mushrooms.
ソースじゃないよ。ソースとか作らんから。
It's not for the sauce. I'm not making a sauce.
こよりのオムライスはケチャップライスと
Koyori's omurice has ketchup rice,
合うからマヨネーズなんで。
and mayonnaise goes well with it.
そう。マヨネーズかけるんで。
Yeah. I'll put mayonnaise on it.
ここはメイド喫茶ですから、やはり、あれでございます。
This is a maid cafe, so of course, it's that.
最後にね、
Finally,
ご主人様のお名前をね、書いて、締めるわけでございますので。
I'll write my master's name on it to finish it off.
そう、初めてのオムライスの時のね、
Yeah, for my first omurice stream,
まだ見てない人いるかもしれないんですけど、
some of you may not have seen it, but...
あの今日待機所にね、しておいた、ショート動画でね、サクッと見ることが出来るんで。
you can watch a short clip of it from the waiting screen.
見たことない人は、こより料理、こよりしゃもじとかで検索すると出てくる
If you haven't seen it, search for Koyori cooking or Koyori rice paddle.
切り抜きもいっぱいある。
There are lots of clips.
そん時はね、あの助手くんって書きたかったんだよね。
Back then, I wanted to write 'Joshu-kun' on it.
助手くんって、メイド喫茶のメイドあの、黄泉のメイドにするのやめてもらっていいか？
Joshu-kun... as a maid in a maid cafe... Can you stop calling me the 'Maid of Hell'?
死なないよ。
I'm not gonna die!
あれ、ちゃんとね、今回はヒベラあるから。
This time, I have a spatula.
ただ、キベラあるから大丈夫だと思って他の器具のこと何も考えてなかったんだけど、
But I thought I'd be fine since I have a spatula and didn't think about other tools.
なんかあの、オムレツを作る時、
Like, when I'm making the omelet,
そのふわふわ卵を作る時、なんかゴムベラでやった方がいいっぽくて。
when making the fluffy eggs, it seems better to use a rubber spatula.
多分柔軟性があるから。
Probably because it's more flexible.
ゴムベラないな。
I don't have a rubber spatula.
木さえあればどうにかなるやろうと思ってて。ゴムベラないなあってなって。
I thought I'd be fine as long as I had a spatula. I see I don't have a rubber spatula.
で、その卵で使うために、はい、マッシュルームね。
So, to use it for the egg... Yes, mushroom!
キベラを、取っとかないといけないから。
I need to set aside the spatula.
チキンライスを、混ぜる時は、
When I'm mixing the chicken rice,
菜箸ですね。菜箸。
I'll use cooking chopsticks. Cooking chopsticks.
木でよくない？木で大丈夫かな？やっぱ柔軟性が必要かなって思ったんだけど。
Is it okay with just a spatula? I think flexibility is needed.
はい、これ切って。これね、ちょっと時短のために、
Okay, cut this. I pre-peeled it to save time.
みんながね、サクサク見られるようにということで、ちょっとやっておきました。皮むくだけはやっておきましたよ。
So you can all watch quickly, I've already peeled it.
え、ちょっと半分かな。半分は、
It's about half, isn't it? Half of it...
えー、ラップでくるんどいて。
I'll wrap it and keep it.
今度、ママあてに持っていこう。
I'll bring it to Mom next time.
ママあてに。
For my mom.
しゃもじは、後で見せてあげるよ、伝説のしゃもじ。
The rice paddle... I'll show you the legendary rice paddle later.
これね、今度ママあてに、お裾分けしますと。
Yeah, I'll give it to my mom next time.
これ、次回以降取ってるから。
I'll keep it for next time.
てかさ、今日さ、連絡来てさ、ママあてから。
You know, I got a message from my mom today.
なんか、今日ちょっと出かけたから、
She said she went out today, so...
えっと、細切れね。今日ちょっと出かけたから、あのカメラ屋さん、覗きに行ったけど、スイッチ２売ってなかったって。
She said, 'I went to a camera shop, but they didn't have the Switch 2.'
連絡くれてさ。
She sent me a message...
ありがとう。頼んでないのに。ありがとうってなった。
Thank you. I didn't even ask her to. Thank you.
えっと、こうか。
Like this...
あ、ふ、そうなんです
Ah, f-, that's right.
ついにはね、家族ぐるみに なりつつあるよ。
It's becoming a whole family affair.
なんか2店舗ぐらい見に行ってくれたらしい。
Apparently, they went to see it at two stores.
優しい。
So kind.
そうで、こよりも今日
Right, and for Koyori too, today...
なんか今日はね、あの インターネッツの在庫が復活する日だったっぽくて
today was the day that the internet stock was apparently going to be restocked.
いや、なんかたまたまだと思うけど、2サイトでね、結構あの、毎日覗いてるけど、まあ在庫復活したらいいなみたいな。
Well, I think it was a coincidence, but on two sites... I check every day, hoping the stock would be back.
たまに復活するサイトがあって
There's a site that restocks occasionally.
そこ見てたらさ、あの 両方ともカートに入れるボタン
When I checked it, the 'Add to Cart' button was displayed for both of them,
まで表示されて、えーってなって
and I was like 'Whaaat?'
で、カートに入れる押すやん。
Then I press 'Add to Cart'.
あの、もうありませんって出るみたいな。
It says it's not available anymore.
そのあの、ギリギリでやってんだろうね、あれね。
They must be doing that right at the last second, huh?
あ、やばい、目痛い！
Oh no, my eyes hurt!
ご主人様！
Master!
ご主人様、もう目が、目が！
Master, my eyes... my eyes!
目が！
My eyes!
やばい！
This is bad!
あ、防護メガネつけとけばよかった。
Ah, I should have worn my protective goggles.
防護メガネ、あのICLやった時の防護メガネ
My protective goggles, the ones from my ICL surgery.
ちょっとしまいこんでるから取りにはいかないけど。
I've put them away, so I won't go get them, though.
バルス！
Balus!
あ、バルスって言ったらこの玉ねぎが微塵切りになればいいのに。
Ah, if only this onion would be minced when I say 'Balus'.
割に結構でも微塵切り上手くできてるんじゃない？
But for what it's worth, I'm dicing this pretty well, don't you think?
バルスされちゃう。
It's gonna get Balus'd.
ああ！ひい！
Aah! Hii!
ああ！
Aah!
ああ！目が！
Aah! My eyes!
痛い！
It hurts!
前に切った時はそんなに痛くなかったのに、これ玉ねぎによるんだろうな。
It didn't hurt this much when I cut one before. It must depend on the onion.
季節にもよるのかな？
Or maybe the season?
それかこよりが勢いよく切りすぎてると跳ねてくるんだろうな、しぶきが。
Or maybe it's because I'm chopping too vigorously that the juices are splashing up.
それでなんか玉ねぎの汁らしいですよね。
They say it's the onion juice, right?
汁が目に入るから染みるんやっていうらしい。
The juice gets in your eyes, and that's why it stings.
みじん切り
Mincing.
ほえ、ほえ、ほえ、ほえ。
Hoei, hoei, hoei, hoei.
え、上手くない？切るの。
Hey, aren't I good at cutting?
なんか前よりも心配しないで見てられてるんじゃないですか？
Aren't you able to watch me with less worry than before?
どうですか？
How is it?
なんか前はもう切るだけで怖えみたいなコメント欄がね、荒れまくってたけど、恐怖で。
Before, just by cutting, the comments section was going wild with fear, like, 'So scary'.
怖い、あれ？
Scary... huh?
もう言う必要もないと思い始めたってこと？
Does that mean you've started to think there's no need to say it anymore?
今でも怖いです。
It's still scary.
うまいね。
Good job.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
そう言ってくれるのは君ぐらいだよ、多分。
You're probably the only one who says that.
でも怖い。
But it's scary.
ほっ。ほっ。ほっ。
Chop. Chop. Chop.
熱い。
It's hot.
なんか何すると熱くなるんだな。一応クーラー入ってるんですけど。
Doing anything makes me hot. Even though the AC is on.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
なんかこれデカいな。よいしょ。
This piece is big. Heave-ho.
ほっ、ほっ、ほっ、ほっ、ほっ、ほっ、ほっ...
Chop, chop, chop, chop, chop, chop...
オッケー。
Okay.
まだある。多いな。
There's still more. This is a lot.
玉ねぎだらけのチキンライスになりそう。
This will be a chicken rice full of onions.
よいしょ。よいしょ。
Heave-ho. Heave-ho.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
でですね、まあ今日ね、ちょっとスイッチツーにこよりが
And so, today, Koyori was...
踊らされてたんで。
...made to dance to its tune.
最新情報。
The latest news.
エアコメじゃない。エアコメなわけないだろ。
It's not a fake comment. How could it be a fake comment?
ちゃんとあるコメントと相対してる。あるコメント読まないとさあ。
I'm interacting with real comments. If I don't read the real comments...
エアコメ読んだって誰も喜ばんじゃん。エアだから。
No one would be happy if I read fake comments. It's just air.
空気しか喜ばん。
Only the air would be happy.
書いてくれてる人がいるから、
I read them because there are people writing them.
読むんだよ。
I read them.
エアコメじゃないの。
They aren't fake comments.
こよりを空気にすんな。
Don't treat Koyori like she's just air.
あー、やばい、目痛い。
Ah, no! My eyes hurt.
こよりが空気なら目痛くないのに。
If Koyori was just air, my eyes wouldn't hurt.
よいしょ。でも空気も痛がってるかもしんないな、この飛沫が。
Heave-ho. But maybe the air is hurting too, from these droplets.
あ、それでね、Switch 2、あ、ちなみになんですけど、話戻るんだけど、その
Oh, and so, the Switch 2... By the way, going back to the topic...
さっきさあ、その入れられそうになった。カートに入れられそうになって入れられなかったって言ったじゃん。
Just now, I said I almost got it. I said I almost got it in my cart but couldn't, right?
で、あれ結構、なんかああいうのって、Switch 2以外でもあると思うんだけど、
And that kind of thing, I think it happens with things other than the Switch 2,
なんか更新してると、こう、カートに入れたけどやっぱ買うのやめましたみたいな人のやつが戻ってきたりするんよ。
when you refresh the page, sometimes an item from someone who put it in their cart but decided not to buy it comes back in stock.
だから、まあ一応カートに入れるボタンも連打して待ち続けてたのね。そしたら、あの
So, I was repeatedly clicking the "Add to Cart" button and waiting. Then, you know...
1回入ったの。
it went into my cart once.
すごくない？
Isn't that amazing?
え、マジでもう興奮して、やばい！1回入った！と思って、
Seriously, I got so excited, like, "No way! It's in the cart!"
で、もう買うぞ！こよりは買うぞ！って思って、決済ボタン
and I thought, "Okay, I'm buying it! Koyori is buying it!" and went for the payment button.
というかカートから進んだの。
Or rather, I proceeded from the cart.
そしたらなんかPayPayが紐付いてて、
Then, it turned out PayPay was linked,
そう、昔買った時のやつで、なんかPayPayになってて
yeah, from something I bought a long time ago, it was set to PayPay.
違う！クレカだ！ってなって、クレカに変えてたら
I was like, "No! It's credit card!" and by the time I changed it to my credit card,
終わりました。いなくなりました、カートから。なんか取られたわ、他の人に。
it was over. It was gone from my cart. Someone else must have snatched it.
ということで、あ、みじん切りもうまくできたんじゃないかな。
Anyway, hey, I think I did a good job dicing this, don't you?
やっぱね、そういうね、残念なことも先ほど50、6時52分ぐらいに
So yeah, that kind of disappointing thing happened earlier at about 6:52...
にね、起きておりましたよと。
so I was awake.
いう、はい、ご主人様。
Yes, Master.
ご主人様。ということで、
Master. And so...
チキンライス用の具材をね、全部コッパ微塵に
I've finely diced all the ingredients for the chicken rice.
しました。イェーイイェーイ。
I did it! Yay, yay!
いいですね。
This is nice.
結構よく切れてる。見た目
It's chopped quite well. The appearance...
その過程を抜かせば見た目はすごくよく切れている。
If you ignore the process, it looks very well-chopped.
それではちょっと、えっと、フライパンのご用意をさせていただきたいと
Now then, I'd like to prepare the frying pan,
思いますので、カメラを一度オフにしまして。
so I'll turn the camera off for a moment.
チキンは？
The chicken?
安心してください。
Don't worry.
こよりが切ってないやつ買ってくるわけないじゃないですか。
Of course Koyori wouldn't buy one that isn't pre-cut.
生もの切るの嫌いなんだから、こより。
I hate cutting raw things, you know.
それじゃあ、ちょっとうるさくなっちゃうんだけど、換気扇を入れたいと思います。
Okay, this might get a little loud, but I'm turning on the vent fan.
今日、ちいちゃん静かだな。遠くを見ている。
Che-chan is quiet today. He's looking off into the distance.
遠くを見ている。うるさいねん。
Looking into the distance. It's loud!
さすがに弱にするか。
I guess I'll turn it down to low.
う、ちょっとうるさすぎたんで、こうして。
It was a bit too loud, so let's do this.
では、ちょっと作り方とか覚えてないけど、
And now, I don't really remember how to make this, but...
ピッ、します。
Beep. It's on.
えー、油と、えっと、あれだ。
Umm... oil and... oh yeah.
用意してなくって思い出した。バターね。
I just remembered something I didn't prepare. The butter.
バター、あ、バター溶けてる。
Butter... Ah, the butter is melting!
やばい。
Oh no.
やばい。バターが、
Oh no. The butter is...
なんで？さっきまで冷蔵庫に入っていたのに。
Why? It was in the fridge until just now.
暑いのか、やっぱ。夏？
Is it because it's hot? Summer?
夏かもしんない。
It might be summer.
よいしょ。バターを、
Heave-ho. The butter...
うおー！
Whoa!
バターが溶けてるだけで美味しそう。
Just watching the butter melt looks delicious.
夏ですからね。しかも、うち、
It is summer, after all. And my...
28度でしかついてないから、うちの暖房、暖房じゃねえや、冷房。
heater is only set to 28 degrees. I mean air conditioner, not heater.
うおー！いいですね。
Whoa! This is nice.
はい、バターを溶かします。
Okay, I'm melting the butter.
ちょっと強いかな？
Is the heat too high?
焦げ付くの怖いから。
I'm afraid it'll burn, so...
そしたら、ここに玉ねぎを入れます。
Then, I'll add the onions.
いいじゃん。
Nice.
ジュージューいって。
It's sizzling.
あ、いい匂い。あ、すごい。すごい、あっちこちに玉ねぎが行った。
Ah, it smells so good! Ah, wow! Wow, the onions went everywhere.
玉ねぎどこ？
Where's the onion?
玉ねぎ、落ちた玉ねぎどこ？
Where's the onion that fell?
猫って玉ねぎダメ？
Are onions bad for cats?
これやばい。よいしょ。あ、あったあった。ここ、ひら。
This is bad. Heave-ho. Ah, found it, found it. Over here.
OK、OK、OK。
Okay, okay, okay.
でね、ゴムベラでこそいでね。
And then, I'll scrape it with a rubber spatula.
おい、さっきの話聞いてたか？うちにはゴムベラなんてものは
Hey, were you listening earlier? I don't have a rubber spatula...
あ、あれ？あれ？
Huh? Wait?
カメラが止まっちゃった。
My camera froze.
あれ？なんで？
Huh? Why?
一回止めて。
Let me stop it for a second.
あれ？
Huh?
あれ、どうした？
Huh, what happened?
あれ？こよりかき混ぜてんのに。
Huh? I'm still stirring though.
ちょ、ちょ、待って待って待って。
Hold on, hold on, wait, wait, wait.
なんで？
Why?
あ、消えた。
Oh, it's gone.
どうした？
What happened?
あー、戻ってきた戻ってきた。よかったよかったよかった。
Oh, it's back, it's back. Thank goodness.
よかったよかったよかった。
Thank goodness, thank goodness.
どうしたんだろう？
I wonder what happened.
え、熱かな？
Was it the heat?
これダイレクト、ダイレクトアタックしてる
The smoke is doing a direct, a direct attack
今、煙が。
on it right now.
やばいかな？
Is this bad?
大丈夫かな？
Is it okay?
ちなみにね、あの、初めての料理配信の時は
By the way, for my first ever cooking stream...
あれだったんですよ。
It was...
あの、まだ1つ前のカメラ使ってて、
I was still using my old camera.
で、これね、カメラの画質めちゃくちゃ良くなったから
This one has way better image quality,
料理配信にはうってつけの状態になってるんじゃないかなと思います。
so I think it's perfect for cooking streams.
カメラがやられた？そんなことあるかな？
Was the camera destroyed? Can that even happen?
たまたま、たまたまだと思うんだけど。
I think it was just a coincidence, though.
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Alright, alright.
どう？あ、でもいい匂い。
How is it? Oh, but it smells good.
バターの香りと玉ねぎの焼けてる香りがめちゃくちゃいいですね。
The smell of butter and frying onions is amazing.
お腹空いてくる。
I'm getting hungry.
そう、この香りだけでね、お腹空いてくるよね。
Yeah, this smell alone makes you hungry, doesn't it?
ねえ。
Right?
防水カメラじゃないとやられるぞ。
"It'll get ruined if it's not a waterproof camera."
うーん、防水じゃないね。
Mmm, it's not waterproof.
ちょっとこうやって湯気を
I'll fan the steam away like this...
でも湯気今換気扇で吸ってるから真上にちょうど行ってるからさ、あの、全部カメラに吸い寄せられてんだけど。
But the fan is sucking it straight up, so... it's all getting sucked towards the camera.
やばい、やばい。
This is bad. This is bad.
思ったより玉ねぎ刻まれてる。なんだと思ってんのこよりのこと。
"The onions are chopped more than I thought." What did you take Koyori for?
ちゃんと切ってたでしょ。
I was cutting them properly, right?
ちょっとでっかいのあるけどね、これね。
Though there is a big one here.
たまに、たまにね、これラッキーみたいな、ラッキー玉ねぎもあります。
Sometimes, there's a lucky, a lucky onion.
これ、でかいやつ。
This big one.
ま、でかいのはね、あの大は小を兼ねるし、でかいのはやっぱ嬉しくなるかな、なんかお得感があっていいんじゃない？
Well, bigger is better, and it makes you happy, right? Like you're getting a bonus. Isn't that nice?
え、飴色になってきてる？
Hey, is it turning golden brown?
どう？
How is it?
ここでね、今日はね、あれなのよ。あの、本番じゃないからね、サクッと作りたい気持ちある。
So, today's not the main event. So I kinda want to cook this up quickly.
ちょっと待って1個こう皿。
Wait, let me get a plate.
いいですね。
Looks good.
ラッキー。なるなる。
Lucky. It is, it is.
え、飴色ってどれ色？
Hey, what color is "golden brown"?
何色？飴色って。
What color is golden brown?
どう？
How's it look?
ちょっと焼きつつ
While I fry it a little...
これがね、前回のオムライスを作った時に、溶けてしまったしゃもじです。
This is the rice paddle that melted when I made omurice last time.
これね、あの、先っちょのところが不自然に、なんかあの、この点々がね、この点々より周りまであるはずやん、普通。
See, the tip is unnaturally... like, these bumps, they should normally go all the way to the edge, right?
つーって切ってふわってなるオムライスIHで初挑戦
First attempt at making a fluffy omelet rice on an IH stove.
つってね。そう、それがこう不自然にちょっと少なくなっているという
Yes. This has gotten unnaturally smaller.
ちょ、ちょっと茶色くなっているというね、これが
It's gotten a little brown too.
なんか、なんか勿体なくってさ。
It just feels like such a waste, you know?
使える時が来るかもしれないと思って、取ってあるんだけど、
I thought a time might come when I could use it, so I kept it.
ま、使うことなんて一回もないんだけど、なんか取ってある。
But I've never used it, not even once. But I just keep it.
もうサトウのご飯しか使ってないからさ。
I only use Sato's pre-cooked rice, so...
あ、待って、ご飯チンしなきゃ。
Oh, wait, I have to microwave the rice.
あ、あ、あ、よいしょ。
Oh, oh, oh. Heave-ho.
はい、いつもお世話になっております、サトウのご飯さんです。
Yes, I'm always indebted to you, Mr. Sato's Rice.
サトウのご飯しか使わないからさ、あのう…ご飯も炊くことさえないのに。
I only use Sato's rice, so... I don't even cook rice myself.
あれでもご飯はまだだ。
The rice isn't ready yet.
したら、え、次、あ、次肉、やばい、焦げる。
Then, uh, next is... ah, the meat! Oh no, it's burning!
次、肉です。よいしょ。
Next up is the meat. Heave-ho.
しゃもじね、うち2個ある。
I have two rice paddles, you know.
引っ越しの時に、買ったやつについてきたやつと
The one that came with what I bought when I moved, and...
待って、ちょ一回切ろう。
Wait, let me turn this off for a second.
引っ越しの時、その実家から一人暮らしするぞって時に
When I moved out from my parents' house to live alone,
買った炊飯器のようなものについてきたしゃもじと
the rice paddle that came with the thing I bought that's like a rice cooker, and...
あと、ママが持たせてくれた、ママあてが持たせてくれたしゃもじが今の溶けたしゃもじね。
the one my mom gave me... the rice paddle from my mom is the melted one now.
真ん中焦げてるよ。
The middle is burning.
ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って。
Wait a sec, wait a sec!
つまり今消してあるから、よいしょ。
I mean, it's turned off now, so... Heave-ho.
ということで、続いてはお肉！はい、細切れです！
So, next up is the meat! Yes, it's chopped!
前回ね、ちょっと唐揚げ用を買ってきたらデカすぎたのをすごいこよりは反省したんで、
Last time, I bought the kind for karaage and it was too big, so Koyori has really learned her lesson.
これ見つけた、細切れ。前回もあったんかな、こんな便利なもの。
I found this, chopped meat. I wonder if they had this last time, something so convenient.
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Heave-ho. Heave-ho.
じゅーっていわない。消してるからね。
It's not sizzling. 'Cause it's turned off.
これを…いい大きさや、やろ？
This... it's a good size, right?
なんか前回の時はこれが視界に入らなかったのかも。
Maybe last time, this just didn't catch my eye.
よいしょ。入れます。
Alright. I'll put it in.
なんかさ、もう切ってある肉はここにあるって、もう、なんか思い込んでいたから、
I was so convinced that the pre-cut meat was in a specific spot,
それ以外のものに目がいかなかった。
that I didn't even look at anything else.
てかこれさ、一緒に炒めてたらさ、玉ねぎ死ぬよね？
But hey, if I sauté these together, the onions will die, right?
玉ねぎって今から死ぬ？ちょっと端っこに寄せよう。
Are the onions going to die now? Let me move them to the side.
あ、でもいい大きさ、いい大きさ。
Ah, but it's a good size, a good size.
こんなね、細切れにしてくれてるのがあるなんて。
To think they have some that's already chopped up like this.
つーって切ってふわってなるオムライスIHで初挑戦
My first try at fluffy slice-open omelet rice on an IH stove
助かる
That helps.
やっぱ生肉切るのってさ、
Cutting raw meat, you know,
なんか衛生上さ、ドキドキしちゃうからさ
it makes me nervous for hygiene reasons.
よし
Alright.
玉ねぎを外すんだよ
You're supposed to take out the onions.
もう外せない
I can't take them out anymore.
もう外せない。
なんか前回は外してた気がする。
I feel like I took them out last time.
前回の方が頭良かった気がする。
I think my brain was working better last time.
逆さにして、
Turn it upside down...
大丈夫かな？
Is this okay?
あれ、外すなんて書いてあったかな？
Huh? Did it say to take them out?
なんとなくね、レシピをさらっと見てきたの、
I kind of just glanced at the recipe.
今見てないけど。
I'm not looking at it now, but...
頭に入れた。頭脳だからね。
I put it in my head. Because I'm a brain, you see.
そう、ご主人様、こよりは頭脳なんです、頭脳。
Right, Master. Koyori is a brain. A brain.
なので、レシピなんて1回読めば
So, if I read a recipe once,
もう覚えちゃうから、見ないで作ってますけど、
I remember it, so I'm cooking without looking...
今回はね、その一応レシピを見たから
This time, I did look at the recipe, so...
なんか、いい感じになると思う。
I think it'll turn out well.
混ざり合うと思う、ちゃんと。
I think they'll mix well.
さすが
As expected.
玉ねぎババア？いや生きてる、生きてる。
Old onion hag? No, they're alive, they're alive.
生きてる、玉ねぎって結構強いんだ、この子達。
They're alive. Onions are pretty tough, these guys.
あと上の方にある子は守られてるから。
And the ones on top are protected.
下の方がちょっと犠牲になる可能性あるけど。
The ones at the bottom might get sacrificed, though.
でもちょっと、あれだよね。あの、
But, you know...
鶏肉はさ、よく焼きしないと、生だとちょっと危ないから。
The chicken must be well-cooked, or it's dangerous if raw.
玉ねぎ、数人犠牲になってもらおう。
Onions, I'll need a few of you to be sacrificed.
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
端っこの方が焼けてない
The ones on the edge aren't cooked.
いやでも細切れだから結構よかった。
But since it's chopped up small, it's pretty good.
前回の唐揚げ大で作ってたら、肉入るまでに玉ねぎが全員死亡してたわ。
If I used big karaage pieces like last time, the onions would have died before the meat was done.
全滅事件になってるところだった。
It would have been a total annihilation incident.
え、いい感じじゃないですか？ご主人様どうです？
Isn't this looking good? How is it, Master?
ご主人様、どうですか？
Master, how is it?
木べらはね、あの、洗うの途中で洗うのめんどくさいんで、
The spatula, well, it's a pain to wash it in the middle,
あの、宝、宝じゃないわ。卵のためにね、あの取っとくから。
so... my treasure, no, not treasure. I'm saving it for the eggs.
あ、いいんじゃない？
Ah, isn't this good?
わ、美味しそう美味しそう。もう美味しいそう。
Wow, it looks delicious. So delicious.
このままだって食べれる。
You could eat it just like this.
ちょっと味全くないけど。
Although it has no flavor at all.
あ、そうだ。
Ah, right.
鶏肉は塩で揉んでから
It said to rub the chicken with salt
焼くって書いてあった。揉みます。
before cooking. I'll rub it.
岩塩。
Rock salt.
前に買ったやつね。
The one I bought before.
こんなもんかな？
Is this about right?
おいしそう。あと塩、胡椒ね。
Looks delicious. And salt, pepper.
胡椒。
Pepper.
いいやつ
The good kind.
ミルのやつね。
The mill kind.
はい、こよりがミルを揉ん
Yes, Koyori is grinding the mill...
入れまーす。オッケー、これでまあ揉まれたということ
I'll put it in. Okay. So this means it's seasoned.
まあまあまあまあ。味ついてるついてる。
Well, well, well. It's seasoned, it's seasoned.
最終的にマヨネーズが味になるから大丈夫よ。
In the end, the mayo on top will add flavor, so it's fine.
美味しそう。
Looks delicious.
まあ食べるのはご主人様ですかな
Well, Master will be the one eating it.
どんなものでもこよちゃんが作ったんだったら
No matter what it is, if Koyori made it,
美味しいって言ってくれるよね。美味しそうじゃない？
you'll say it's delicious, right? Doesn't it look tasty?
いい感じ、今そぼろみたいになってるけど。なんかボロボロで。
It looks good. It's like minced meat, kind of crumbled.
そしたらここに、マッシュルームさんを加えまーす。
Then, I'll add the mushrooms.
やばい。
Oh no.
ガラスに熱が加わる。
The heat is getting to the glass.
マッシュルームを入れるとすごい香りよくなりそうだけど
Adding mushrooms seems like it would smell really good, but...
どうかな
I wonder.
うーん。ふん。うーん。鼻水出てきた。
Mmm. Hmm. Mmm. My nose is starting to run.
あったかくて鼻水出てきた。
It's warm, so my nose is running.
うーん。あんま匂い分からなくなってきた。
Mmm. I can't really smell it anymore.
もう匂い分からなくなってきた。
I can't smell it anymore.
ピーマンはね、ラストです、ラスト。
The green peppers are last, last.
こんな感じ
Like this.
これマッシュルーム、火、入ってる？
Are these mushrooms cooked?
火、入ってる？
Are they cooked?
でも茶色っぽくなってるから元々茶色いけど。
Well, they're turning brownish, though they were brown to begin with.
入ってるだろう。
They're probably cooked.
さて、ピーマンも入れまーす。
Okay, I'll add the green peppers too.
コンソメを入れたっていい？
Should I add consommé?
この場にコンソメがあったら「本当？」って入れてあげるけど
If I had consommé here, I'd say "Really?" and add it, but...
コンソメなんてうちにあるわけがなかった。
of course I don't have any at home.
多分。料理配信でコンソメ使ったことないもんね。
Probably. I haven't used consommé in my cooking streams.
え、なんか炒め物みたいじゃん、見た目。
Hey, it looks like a stir-fry.
あ、炒め物か今炒めてるから。
Oh, it is a stir-fry since I'm stir-frying it.
やばい、玉ねぎが黒くなってきた。
Oh no, some of the onions are turning black.
やばい。
This is bad.
まあ後でケチャップでびちょびちょになるから。
Well, it'll be drenched in ketchup later, so you won't notice.
オッケーオッケーオッケー。
Okay, okay, okay.
ああ、ピーマンのいい香り。
Ah, the nice smell of green peppers.
いいな、やっぱピーマンっていいよね。
Nice. Green peppers are great, aren't they?
ピーマンはワンチャン生でも食べれるようなものだから
Green peppers are something you could possibly eat raw,
まあ、まあこんなもんでオッケーかな。
so this should be fine.
ちょっとコンソメあるか見てみるか。
Let me see if I have any consommé.
コンソメ…
Consommé...
パッと見ない
I don't see any.
どうしましたら。
What should I do?
続きまして、美味しいコツみたいなのを見たんで。
Next up, I saw a tip for making it delicious.
まずトマトケチャップ。小さいのがあったので買いました。
First, tomato ketchup. I found a small one, so I bought it.
使い切らないからね。
I won't use it all up, you see.
マヨラーはケチャップ使う機会が少ないんですよ。
You see, a mayo lover rarely uses ketchup.
えっと、大さじ1杯。
Um, one tablespoon.
こんなもんかな。まあ味濃い方がおいしいっすね。
This should be enough. A stronger flavor is tastier, right?
で、ま、ケチャップじゃないですか。
So, first, ketchup, you know?
そしてですね、続きまして、こちら、トマトペースト。
And then, next up, this. Tomato paste.
これなんか多分、あの、ケチャップよりもよりトマトな
This is probably, um, more tomato-y than ketchup.
もので、これ1本大さじ1杯なんだけど、このトマトペーストを入れると風味良くなるらしい
This stick is one tablespoon. I hear that adding this tomato paste improves the flavor.
よいしょ。足りないと思ったでしょう？
There we go. You thought it wasn't enough, didn't you?
合わせ技なんです。今日はね、
It's a combination technique. Today, I'm making...
そう、最、最高級タンポポオムライスだから、ちょっと味にもこだわって。
...the most, the most high-class Tampopo Omurice, so I'm being particular about the flavor too.
はい。で、混ぜます。
Right. And now I'll mix it.
で、この具材の間に混ぜてしまうのがいいらしい。
Apparently, it's best to mix it in with the ingredients like this.
この前さ、あの、前回はさ、レシピなしで作ってたんだけど、そん時はあの、お米投入してから混ぜようとしたんだよね。あまりにも大変だった。
The other day, last time, I made it without a recipe. Back then, I tried to mix it after adding the rice. It was way too difficult.
あまりにも混ぜるの大変だった。これをこうやって混ぜておくと、具材に混ざってるから、後で混ざりやすいっぽい。
Mixing it was so hard. If you mix it like this first, it mixes with the ingredients, so it seems easier to mix in later.
火を止めろと言われていたが、ま、大丈夫やろ。今弱火、あ、中火、中火だし。
I was told to turn off the heat, but it should be fine. It's on low, no, medium heat. It's on medium heat.
そう、これで美味しそう。もうこのまま食べたって美味しい。ま、味見はしない。
Yes, this looks delicious. It would be tasty even if I ate it as is. Well, I won't taste it.
それでは、え、ご飯200g。サトウのごはんね。
Alright, 200g of rice. It's Sato's pre-cooked rice.
なんかケチャップ飛んでんな。え、ってことはこれ服に飛んでる？やば。
The ketchup is splattering. Wait, did it get on my clothes? Oh no.
ま、エプロンだからええか。
Well, I'm wearing an apron, so it's fine.
それでは、行きます。ふっ！
Alright then, here I go. Whoosh!
はい。お米を落として。混ざるかなー。
Okay. Drop in the rice. I wonder if it'll mix well.
うおおー！
Woah!
で、もう火止めて。あ、弱火にするわ。そっか。でも、
Okay, I'll turn off the heat now. Oh, I'll set it to low. I see. But...
じゃ保温でやるわ。米って、火入れなくても食えるから、火止めていいのか。
I'll just keep it warm. You can eat rice without heating it, so it's fine to turn off the heat.
混ざるかな？ヘラじゃないけど。この、
Will it mix? It's not a spatula, but... This...
箸で、ほっ。うーん。
With chopsticks... there. Mmm.
あっ！
Ah!
ね、この新衣装に付けたくないよ。
I don't want to get it on my new outfit.
今日はね、あの、ワンピースなんで、この服。下もちゃんと履いてます。履いてますっていうか、ワンピースです。
Today, I'm wearing a one-piece dress, this outfit. I'm wearing something underneath too. I mean, it's a one-piece dress.
だから飛んだら、こよりの足じゃなくて、ワンピースに飛んでしまうから、そっちの方を避けたい。
So if it splatters, it won't hit Koyori's legs, it'll hit the dress, so I want to avoid that.
パンイチじゃないの？着てるの見えるでしょ？
Not just in your underwear? You can see I'm dressed, right?
この前はね、あの、上と下が分かれてたから、下はパンイチだったけど。
Last time, my top and bottom were separate, so I was just in my underwear on the bottom.
あ、なんかじゅーって言わないの寂しい。
Ah, it's kind of sad that it's not sizzling.
混ざる。
It's mixing.
つーって切ってふわってなるオムライスIHで初挑戦
First attempt at a fluffy, slice-open omurice on an IH stove.
どう？
How's it looking?
わかった
I got it.
わかったわ
今、えっと、消せば
Now, uhm, if I turn it off...
しゃもじで混ぜたっていいよね？
It's fine to mix with a rice paddle, right?
ね。よし。あんま下に…あ、飛んだ
Right. Okay. Not too much on the... ah, it flew out.
あんま下に付かないように気をつけて
I have to be careful not to let it stick to the bottom.
ほ
Hup.
もう冷めてるから。余熱で
It's already cooling down. With the residual heat.
大丈夫。混ぜてるだけだから
It's okay. I'm just mixing.
痛めてない
I'm not frying it.
オッケー
Okay.
取っといてよかった。こういう時のためのしゃもじやな
Good thing I kept this. This rice paddle is for times like these.
木べらはね、この後登場するから
The wooden spatula, you see, will appear later.
ちゃんと火使うときは木べら使うから
When I actually use the heat, I'll use the wooden spatula.
さあ、これをですね、盛り付けたい
Now, this... I want to plate it.
よいしょ。盛り付けるには
Heave-ho. To plate it...
一旦じゃあ、ちょっと待ってな
First, please wait a moment.
カメラを閉じて
I'll close the camera.
あ、落ちてるやつ食べたけどおいしい
Ah, I ate the piece that fell and it's delicious.
猫の毛ついてた
It had cat hair on it.
なんかさ、IHってさ、あの、静電気ある？
You know, this IH stove... does it have static electricity?
シーコヨのさ、毛がさ、ものすごい、あの、登ってないのに
Chiikoyo's fur... it's incredible. Even though he's not on it...
ものすごいね、あるんだよ
...there's an incredible amount of it.
なんかちょっと多くない？一人分
Isn't this a bit much for one person?
よそおう
Let's serve it up.
え、おいしそう
Whoa, it looks delicious.
もうこのまま食べれるチキンライス
This is chicken rice I could eat just as it is.
まず成形しないといけない
First, I have to shape it.
ちょっと待って
Wait a moment.
えっと、これは
Uhm, this is...
あ、つまんだ
Ah, I picked it up.
つまんだ落ちたチキンライスについてた毛が
I picked up the hair that was on the fallen chicken rice...
猫の毛が
...the cat hair.
こうですね。ほ、ほ
Like this. Hop, hop.
え、おいしそう
Whoa, it looks delicious.
ちょっと多い
It's a little much.
でも、オムレツを上に受け止めないと行けないから
But I have to make it so it can hold the omelet on top.
広め、平らめ
Wider, flatter.
つーって切ってふわってなるオムライスIHで初挑戦
My first attempt at a fluffy, perfectly cut omurice using an IH stove
また皿が汚くなる。
The plate is getting dirty again.
お... お... お... お...
Oh... oh... oh... oh...
どんなもん？べしべし。べしべし。
How's this? Pat pat. Pat pat.
え、なんかうまそう。
Oh, it looks delicious.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
でも全部よそっちゃっていいかな？
But should I serve it all?
米200gってこんなに多かったっけ？
Was 200g of rice really this much?
でっかい。ね、まだこんなにあんだけど。
It's huge. And there's still this much left.
やばいこれ。でかすぎ？
This is insane. Is it too big?
ちょっと別の皿にもっとくか。明日の朝ごはんにしよう。
Maybe I should put some on another plate. I'll have it for breakfast tomorrow.
めっちゃ多いやん。
It's so much!
ほとんど細切れにした野菜だけなのに、こんなに多くなるんだ。
Even though it's mostly chopped vegetables added in, it becomes this much.
家庭的なところ見えちゃった。明日の朝ごはんね。
You saw my domestic side. Breakfast for tomorrow.
え、でも、すごいおいしそうだよ。
But, wow, it looks so delicious.
いい香りだし。ちゃんとね、ケチャップ、トマトペーストも全体に馴染んでるわ。
It smells good, too. And the ketchup and tomato paste are mixed in evenly.
素晴らしい。
Wonderful.
さあ、もうちょっと、余分なの食べる。
Now, let's eat the leftover.
うん。
Mhm.
あ、コクがある。
Oh, it has a rich flavor.
ちょっと水入れます。
I'm adding some water.
え、めっちゃおいしい！
Wow, it's so delicious!
あ、待って、なんでシャモジ、こより、やったの？まだ整形してないのに。
Oh, wait, why did Koyori use the rice paddle like that? I haven't even shaped it yet.
はい、これが二本目のシャモジね。
Okay, this is the second rice paddle.
あ、二本目のシャモジ、後ろボコボコしてるから、整形しづらい。
Oh, the back of the second paddle is bumpy, so it's hard to shape.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
これで、ちょっと、上を平らにしとかないと、着地点が...
With this, I need to flatten the top, or the landing spot...
こんなもんかな？
Is this about right?
オッケー。よし。
Okay. Alright.
二代目シャモジね、これね。ま、二代目シャモジも別に使われてないんですけど。
This is the second-generation rice paddle. Well, the second-generation one isn't being used either, though.
で、みんなに文句言われるから、この周りを拭きます。
And, because everyone will complain, I'll wipe the edges.
皿が汚ねぇって。
Because they'll say the plate is dirty.
言われるから。ご主人様、ご主人様結構ね、ハイ嗜好だから。
My masters, my masters have pretty high standards.
お... お... お...
Oh... oh... oh...
お...
Oh...
拭くのって難しいよね。
Wiping is hard, isn't it?
米がついてくる。
The rice keeps sticking to it.
食べて。
Eating it.
つーって切ってふわってなるオムライスIHで初挑戦
My first attempt at a fluffy omelet rice on an IH stove.
よし、できた！おいしそう！
Alright, it's done! It looks delicious!
ええ、おいしそう！あったかい。
Yeah, it looks delicious! It's warm.
あったかいんだから〜
Because it's wa~rm♪
ケチャップしまって。
Putting away the ketchup.
それででは続きまして、
And now, moving on...
本日のメインディッシュ。
to today's main dish.
ええ、卵行きたいと思います。
Yes, I'd like to get started on the eggs.
ええ、ふわふわ卵を作るときは牛乳を混ぜるんですけど、
Yes, when making fluffy eggs, you mix in milk.
これ15ccね、あの、すでに測っておきました。
This is 15cc. I've already measured it out.
ちなみにうちにある計量は、この、このシャモジの後ろのここだけです。
By the way, the only measuring tool I have is this part on the back of this rice paddle.
あ、ここに小さじあんじゃん。
Oh, there's a teaspoon here.
ちょうどいいじゃん。
That's perfect.
小さじがあれば３杯測れば大さじだし、
If I have a teaspoon, three of these make a tablespoon.
これで行けるじゃんと思って、あの、
I thought I could manage with this, so...
一人暮らし最初からこれしか使ってない。
I've only used this since I started living alone.
この、この小さじだけで生きてきた。
I've survived with just this teaspoon.
え、ここにですね、卵を３つ。
And into this, I'll add three eggs.
やばい。
Oh no.
あ、布の、布のあれがびちょびちょ。
Oh, the cloth... the cloth is all wet.
あー！びっくりした！
Ah! That scared me!
投げちゃったよ今。
I just threw it.
びっくりした。
That scared me.
よいしょ。計量カップはね、あの、あれ。
There we go. As for the measuring cup... um, that.
やばい。ちょ、これ、ちいこよの毛です。
Oh no. Hey, this is Chieko's fur.
あの、計量カップ...ね、ちいこよの毛が取れない。
Um, the measuring cup... Hey, Chieko's fur won't come off.
やばい。おっし、よし。オッケー。
Oh no. Okay, okay. Alright.
計量カップはあの
The measuring cup is, um...
あー！びちょびちょ。もうだめだ。
Ah! It's soaked. This is no good.
洗濯しなきゃ。このカード開封もやってるやつなのに、
I have to wash it. This is the one I use for card openings,
もうびちょびちょ。
and now it's soaked.
また毛が、毛がついてる。
There's fur on it again, there's fur.
あのね、
You know...
さっきさあ、あの、しゃもじが2個あったじゃないですか。
earlier... there were two rice paddles, right?
しゃもじが2個あるっていうことは米の計量カップも2個あるわけよ。
And if there are two rice paddles, that means there are two rice measuring cups.
あ、菜箸1本しかないかも。
Oh, I might only have one cooking chopstick.
菜箸1本しかないから、
Since I only have one cooking chopstick,
ちょっと普通の箸で混ぜます。
I'll just mix it with regular chopsticks.
はい、混ぜますけど。
Okay, I'm mixing it.
そう、お米の計量カップも2つあったので、
Right, I had two rice measuring cups, so...
だから1つのお米、1つの計量カップはお米で使用して、
one measuring cup was used for rice,
もう1つの計量カップは計量カップとして使用してたのね。
and the other one was used as an actual measuring cup.
菜箸1本なんてことある？
How can I only have one cooking chopstick?
1本だって全然使わないんだから。
I don't even use one.
この配信でしか使わないんだから菜箸。
I only use cooking chopsticks for this stream.
そうで、あの、それがね、なんかね、引っ越した時に無くなっちゃったんだよね。
And so, um, that one... I think I lost it when I moved.
どっか行っちゃった。
It's gone somewhere.
なんかこの家に来てから計量カップ無くなっちゃった。
I feel like I lost the measuring cup after moving into this house.
前の計量カップまでは、あのあったんだけど
I had a measuring cup at my old place
あったんだけど
but...
そう。前、じゃ、前の計量カップまでってなに？
Wait, 'at my old measuring cup'?
前の家まではね、あったんだけど、捨てられたかな？
I meant at my old house. I had one, but maybe I threw it away?
あれ？これゴミかなって思って、捨てられちゃったかな？そんなことないか。
Like, 'Huh? Is this trash?' and threw it out? Probably not.
どっか行っちゃった。置いといてきたかも、こよりが。
It went somewhere. Maybe I left it behind.
そんなことない。ダンボールに入ってるわ。
No, that's not it. It's in a cardboard box.
そんなことないわ。計量カップマジでどこ行ったんだろう。
That's not it. I seriously wonder where my measuring cup went.
この卵は、よく混ぜないと行けない。
This egg needs to be mixed well.
でもだいぶもう混ざってるかな。
But it looks pretty well-mixed now, I think.
ここからがね、本番なんだけど
From here on out is the real thing, but...
ここはね、めっちゃ早いよ。20秒とかだから焼くの。
this part is super fast. It only takes like 20 seconds to cook.
よし。じゃあ一旦カメラ落として
Alright. I'll turn off the camera for a bit.
半熟じゅくじゅくでね、やりたいんで
I want to make it nice and runny, so...
えー、焼いてる時間、すごく短いです。
Uh, the cooking time will be very short.
もう、もうできます。
It's... It'll be done soon.
ドキドキ
My heart's pounding.
ドキドキドキドキよ、ドキドキドキドキ。
My heart's pounding, pounding, pounding.
ほいしょ。
Here we go.
したら、え、オリーブオイルですね。
Next, uh, is the olive oil.
リーブオイル量知りません。
I don't know how much olive oil to use.
熱します。
I'll heat it up.
あ、何火だろう？
Oh, what heat level should I use?
何火か知らないですけど
I don't know what heat level to use, but...
何火だ？
What heat level?
これ新しいフライパンね。これのために買ったから。
This is a new frying pan. I bought it just for this.
これがIHで、その、オムレツ、オムライスを作るのにいいやつなんだって。
They say this is a good one for making omelets, omurice on an IH stove.
おすすめをちゃんと買いましたんで。
I made sure to buy the recommended one.
強火？
High heat?
じゃあ強火にする。この温めてるだけの時間においしそうなチキンライスを挟み込みながら、ヘラの準備、ヘラの準備。
Okay, high heat. While it's heating, I'll show the chicken rice and get a spatula.
ちーちゃん、オムライスちょっとでできるよ
Chii-chan, the omurice will be ready in a bit.
ふーんって顔で見てきた。今日鳴かないね。
He looked at me with a 'hmph' face. He's not meowing today.
ねえ、前すごい泣いてたのにね。あの、モンハン飯作ったとき。
Right? He was crying so much before. When I made the MonHun meal.
モンハン飯はやっぱアイルーだから
The MonHun meal is because of the Felynes, I guess.
あ、待って。これなんか菜箸がフツフツしてきたら、温度OKみたいな書いてあったんだけど、菜箸じゃないから
Oh, wait. It said the temp is okay when the chopsticks bubble, but I'm not using them.
いけるやろ。行きます！
It should be fine. Here I go!
あ、ジュワっていった。オッケー。
Oh, it sizzled. Okay.
あ、菜箸で混ぜるんじゃん！
Oh, you're supposed to mix it with chopsticks!
えーと、ま、え、で、内側から外側に向けて混ぜる。
Uh, well, okay, so, mix from the inside out.
つーって切ってふわってなるオムライスIHで初挑戦
My First Attempt at Making a Cut-and-Fluff Omelet
3、4、5、6、7、
3, 4, 5, 6, 7,
8、9、10、
8, 9, 10,
11、12、13、14、
11, 12, 13, 14,
15、16、17、
15, 16, 17,
18、19、20。
18, 19, 20.
待って、まだドゥルドゥルじゃない？
Wait, isn't it still runny?
でも周りが固まってるから
But the edges are setting, so...
え、これで… あ、やばい。
So, with this... Oh no.
え、どうやんの？これ。
Huh? How do I do this?
こっちから… あれ？
From this side... Huh?
あれ？
Huh?
ヘラで… よし。
With the spatula... okay.
よし。
Okay.
あ…
Ah...
こう、こう、こう、こう。あー、ちょっと焼けてく、焼けてく！
Like this, this, this... Ah, it's burning, it's burning!
ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って！
Wait, wait!
ちょ、ちょ、ちょ、ちょ、して、こうしてこぼれる。
W-w-w-wait... and it's spilling.
あ！
Ah!
ああ！どういうこと？
Aah! What's happening?!
あ、ここパキパキ、あ、パキパキになっちゃった
Oh, this part's crispy. It's gotten all crispy!
え、強火って言ったの誰？パキパキになってる。
Huh? Who said to use high heat? It's all crispy.
あ！
Aah!
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
え、全然まとまんないよ。
Huh? It's not coming together at all.
同じフライパン、同じ量の卵なのに、お手本と。
It's the same pan, the same amount of egg as the example.
こうして、で、こっちからこうして
Like this, and then from this way, like this...
あー！あふれてる！あふれちゃう！
Aah! It's overflowing! It's gonna spill!
待って！待ってよ！どうして？
Wait! Wait! Why?
ねえ、どうして？
Hey, why?
どうして？
Why?
でもまだ回る、まだ回る。これで固めながら
But I can still... I can still. I'll let it set as I go,
固めながらにして
letting it set...
よし。
Okay.
なんであふれちゃうのお前は
Why are you overflowing?
ねえ、ちょ…
Hey, wai-
で、こっちも剥がして
Then, peel this side too...
あー！
Aah!
じゅくじゅくなんだっけど
It's all wet though.
え、まだ回るな、まだ半熟だからこれを閉じれさえすれば
Huh, I can still do it. It's still runny, so if I can just close it...
回る。色悪いけど。
I can. The color is bad, though.
マヨネーズで文字書く時に見やすくていいかな。
Maybe it'll be easy to see when I write on it with mayo.
え、なんで固まんないの？
Huh? Why won't it set?
なんで固まんないんだ？
Why won't it set?
で、こう、閉じるんですけど
So, I'll close it like this...
え？
Huh?
やっぱゴムベラじゃないとダメなのかな？
Maybe I need a rubber spatula?
この右下からこうやってやっていって、左下からこうやってやっていって
From the bottom right, I'll do this, and from the bottom left, I'll do this...
閉じれたらこれで閉じて...
If I can close it, I'll close it like this...
つーって切ってふわってなるオムライス IHで初挑戦
Tornado Omelet: First attempt on an IH stove
閉じて、閉じて
Close it, close it.
閉じたら
Once it's closed,
逆さにする
flip it over.
逆さに
Upside down...
して、後ろを閉じる。
and close the back.
ゴム、ゴムベラじゃないから。
A rubber... it's not a rubber spatula.
やっ、えっ？木じゃだめなの？
Wait, eh? Can't I use a wooden one?
手べらも入れる、手べら。あちい！
I'll use my hand spatula. Hot!
で、これで、逆さにする
And with this, I'll flip it over.
逆さにできる気が全然しない。
I have no confidence I can flip it.
てか逆さにしたらこの半熟が全部逃げる
Besides, if I flip it, all this runny egg will escape.
こうだ。こうやってちょっと押さえよう。
Like this. I'll hold it down a bit like this.
こう行って、
Go like this...
こう、あ。もう手、あ。
Like... ah. My hand, ah.
おいしょ。ういしょ。
Heave-ho. Heave-ho.
これでちょっと行ってみよう。
With this, let's give it a try.
うーん。
Mmm...
閉じろ。あ、閉じそう。
Close. Ah, it's about to close.
これで閉じれれば
If it closes with this...
助けてママって。ママってもうこんなの作ったことないんじゃない？
Help me, Mama. Mama's probably never made one of these.
ないと思う。こよは食べたことない、ママの手のタンポポオムライス。
I don't think so. I've never had Mama's Tampopo omurice.
え、この、このぶよぶよの卵が全部こぼれそうなんだけど。
Hey, this... all this jiggly egg looks like it's going to spill.
えっと、これで
Um, with this...
逆さに
Flip it...
ひっくり返すって
Flip it over...
むずか
So hard.
ああー！うーん。
Aahh! Mmm...
逆さにして閉じないとこぼれちゃうから。
If I don't flip and close it, it'll spill.
うー！うー。ちょっと待って、これ食べよう。
Oof! Oof. Wait, let me eat this.
あつい！
Hot!
よいしょ！あ、いいいいいい。いい。もう、こんなん
Heave-ho! Ah, nice, nice, nice. Good. Oh, what is this...
こんなに
This is...
で、これで5秒ぐらいしたら、後ろを
And, after about 5 seconds, the back...
後ろがくっつくからこうやってで、あとは余熱で
The back will stick, so I'll do this, and then let it cook with the residual heat.
おおおおお。ちょっとオムレツっぽい、オムレツっぽい。
Oooh. It's kinda like an omelet, like an omelet.
OK、OK。で、多分後ろが閉じたから
OK, OK. And, since the back probably closed,
え、これをもう一回
uh, this one more time...
ひっくり返す。
Flip it.
え、いいんじゃない？
Hey, isn't this good?
いいんじゃない？
Isn't this good?
なんか、いい感じになってきた。
It's starting to look pretty good.
そしたら、えっと、これを、
So then, um, this...
よいしょ。
Yo.
ほっ。
Whoa.
上に乗せるわけですよ。
You put it on top.
ナイスリカバー。
Nice recovery.
これどれくらい下の方固まっちゃってんのかな。
I wonder how much the bottom has set.
ここに、乗せる！おお！え、いいんじゃない？
Here. Put it on! Wow! Hey, isn't this good?
とろーってなるかな？
Will it be all runny?
出来上がったら鳴き始めたね、ついちゃん。
Tsuichi started meowing when it was done.
乗ったよ、しかも。
And it went on so smoothly!
かけらがこうしてちょっと、なんか場所が悪いから
There's a crumb... The position is a bit off.
手で場所移動しよう。
Let's move it with my hand.
やれたか？
Did I do it?
やれたか、これ？
するーんとぅるーんとぅるーんって開けば、開いたらたんぽぽオムライスです。
If I cut it open, it'll be a dandelion omelet.
見た目いい感じだけどな。こんな感じ。
It looks pretty good. Like this.
ええやん。
Looks good.
で、この状態で、えっと、助手くんって書く。
And then, in this state, um, I'll write 'Joshu-kun'.
どこやった？あった。
Where did I put it? Ah, there it is.
今日はですね、ここで、
Today, at this point...
え、こよちゃんトリュフ大好きなんですね。芳醇トリュフ味のマヨネーズをご用意させて頂きました。
Koyo loves truffles. I've prepared some rich truffle-flavored mayonnaise.
これ初めて食べる。ずっと気になってたんだよ。なんかね、最近ね、この世界を味わうマヨシリーズって言うのが、キューピーさんから出てて、
This is my first time eating this. I've been curious about it for a while. You know, recently, this 'Savor the World Mayo Series' has been out from Kewpie.
そう、絶対美味しいやろうと思い、気になっていたトリュフの香りのする。
Yeah, I thought it must be delicious. I was curious about this truffle-scented...
トリュフの香りする
truffle-scented...
で、多分この小さいサイズだったら穴が一つだと思うんだよね。
And, I think with this small size, there's only one hole, right?
最高！穴一つ！
The best! One hole!
かけてかける。
I'll put it on.
よいしょ。
Here we go.
今回くんまでかけるのでは
I'll draw until the 'kun' part this time.
やっぱ感じて難しいな。
Kanji is hard, after all.
場所取る。
It takes up space.
と、できた！
And... it's done!
できた、助手くん、できました！
It's done! Joshu-kun! It's finished!
じゃ、これで写真撮っとこ。
Okay, I'll take a picture of this.
写真ね。大事写真。かけてる、かけてる。
Photo time. The picture is important. I'm drawing, I'm drawing.
こよりこういうのうまいんだから。
Koyori is good at this kind of thing.
よいしょ。じゃ写真撮ります。はい。
Alright. I'm taking a picture now. Okay.
ポートレート。
Portrait mode.
あ、ポートレートになっちゃう。まぁいっか。
Ah, it's going into portrait mode. Well, whatever.
はい、助手くん！はい、チーズ
Okay, Assistant-kun! Say cheese!
ずー。なんか全体的に茶色いな。
Zooom. It looks kind of brown overall.
で。
And then...
えぇ...
Umm...
これ生のもの切ったやつだから、1回包丁も一個しかない。
Since I used this to cut raw stuff, I'll use another knife.
じゅーって言ってる。包丁水で洗って。
Did you hear that sizzle? I washed the knife with water.
ここからよね。
This is it, right?
開くのか。でも結構最後のほうまでトロトロしてたからいける気がするけど。
Will it open? It was pretty runny till the end, so I think it'll work.
それではタンポポオムライスの本番です。
Alright then, this is the main event for the Tampopo Omurice.
皆さん、ご開帳いきたいと思います。
Everyone, I'm going to open it up.
行くぞ！
Here I go!
あ、待って。助手くん！はい、召し上がれ。
Ah, wait. Assistant-kun! Here you go, enjoy your meal.
このね、この状態、この状態一回撮って、一回撮って。
Let me take a picture of it in this state first. Let me take it.
あ、最後に愛を注入してない。せーの、愛を、ぴょん。
Ah, I haven't injected my love at the end. Ready, set, a bit of love.
オッケー。
Okay.
それでは開きます。
And now, I'll open it.
ほ。
Whoa.
うーん、この時点でもうトロっといくはずなんだけど。
Hmm, it should be runny by now.
あ？
Ah...
あっ...
あれ？あれ？
Huh? Huh?
おかしいな。割れちゃったな、真ん中まで。
That's weird. It split all the way to the middle.
切れ味が良すぎたかな。
Maybe the knife was too sharp?
あ、でも... ちょっと待って。
Ah, but... wait a minute.
開けば、なんか...
If I open it, it's kind of...
それ、あ、トリフの濃厚な香りがするマヨネーズがついた指先をなめたら、過去布越しに...
It's, ah, when I licked my fingertip that has truffle-scented mayo on it... through the cloth...
ふわとろ詐欺。
A fluffy-gooey scam.
これ詐欺に入りますか？これ。
Does this count as a scam?
がサムネ。サムネ詐欺。
Thumbnail scam. Thumbnail scam.
ちょ、助手くんの内臓をえぐってるみたいな。
It's like I'm gouging out Assistant-kun's organs...
あ、肝臓ってこういう形してんのよね。ちょっと、あの...
The liver is shaped like this, isn't it? Uh, well...
細長い三角形みたいな。
Like a long, narrow triangle.
つーって切ってふわってなるオムライスIHで初挑戦
My First Attempt at a Fluffy Omurice that You Cut Open
うーん
Hmm...
やめてください。死んでしまいます。
Please stop. I'll die.
助手くんの名前が書かれた肝臓を
I feel like I'm opening up a liver
開いているような
with an assistant's name written on it,
手術をしているような気持ちになってきたな。
like I'm performing surgery.
うーん
Hmm...
あれ、さっきまであのトロトロだったのはどこ行ったんだ？
Huh? Where did that runny texture from earlier go?
余熱しか当ててないはずなんだけど。
I should have only used residual heat.
やっぱ強火って言ったのが間違いだったんじゃないか？
Maybe saying 'high heat' was the mistake?
うーん
Hmm...
思ってたんと違う。えっ？
This is different from what I expected. Huh?
えっ？
Huh?
メイドさんにそんなこと言うんですか？
Is that what you say to a maid?
うーん
Hmm...
丹精込めて作りました。
I made this with great care.
ふわとろ、
A fluffy, runny,
ふわとろタンポポオムライスです、ご主人様。
Tampopo-style omurice, Master.
どうでしょうか？
What do you think?
強火？
High heat?
ワザップ？
Wazap?
フライパンの上に置きすぎ？ま、確かに。
Left it on the frying pan too long? Well, that's true.
確かにあの包み込めなくって何十秒もいた。
I couldn't wrap it and it sat there for a while.
一応弱火にしたけどその時は。
I did turn it down to low heat at the time, though.
はい。
Yes.
ふわとろ、
It's a fluffy, runny...
ふわとろオムライスなんですけど。
...omurice, but...
どうですか？
How is it?
多分これちょっとマヨネーズが足りないと思うので
I think it needs a bit more mayonnaise, so...
皿も汚い！
The plate is dirty!
だって今開いたんだもん。
That's because I just cut it open!
よいしょ。シュー。ちょっとくまで書いとくあれだからね。
Here we go. *Squeeze*. I'll just draw a bear on it.
はい、助手。
There, "Assistant".
どうでしょう？ちょ、見づらいですね。
How's that? It's a bit hard to see.
さっきのこんがり焼きはこのマヨネーズが読みやすいようにという配慮のもとで、ちょっとこんがりさせていただいたので。
I browned it a bit as a consideration to make the mayonnaise easier to read.
え、食べたいよ。
Hey, I want to eat it.
食べたい？
You want to eat it?
どうですか？
How is it?
皿拭くよ。皿。
I'll wipe the plate. The plate.
助手。
Assistant.
これ2回目なんでね、愛を注ぐの。
This is the second time I'm pouring my love into it.
まぁ、雑にもなりますよね。
Well, it's bound to get a little messy.
時短ね、時短。
Saving time, saving time.
この状態も写真撮っとくか。開いた状態。
Maybe I'll take a picture of it like this, too. In its opened state.
あ、助手くん様、召し上がれ。
Ah, Mr. Assistant, please eat.
え、えへ、えへ、えへへ。
Eh? Hehe, hehe, hehe.
最高級たんぽぽオムライス
This top-class tanpopo omurice...
ちょっと食べてみますか。実食してみたいと思います。
shall I try it? I'd like to do a taste test.
食べたい。
I wanna eat it.
そうだよな。つかね、今日はね、あれだと思う。
Right? You know, for today, I think...
もうちょっとマヨネーズが足りない。
It needs a little more mayonnaise.
多分ね、チキンライスがめちゃくちゃ美味しそうだから、あの…
I think the chicken rice looks incredibly delicious, so...
チキンライスで評価が上がる気がする。
I feel my rating will go up because of the chicken rice.
前回も別にふわとろじゃなかったしな。
The last one wasn't fluffy either, after all.
ほい。
Here we go.
ケチャップライスがね、めっちゃ美味しそう。
The ketchup rice looks so delicious.
やっぱレシピ見るって大事なんだな。
Following a recipe is important, I see.
この卵の部分もレシピ見たんだけど
I looked at a recipe for the egg part too.
あれ、チキンライスよそえてない。
Huh? I didn't scoop any chicken rice.
想像以上に分厚すぎてチキンライスまで取れてない。
It's thicker than I imagined, so I couldn't get to the chicken rice.
いただきます。
Time to eat.
美味しそう。
It looks delicious.
んー！
Mmm!
あ、味はね、前回の50倍くらいうまい。
Ah, the taste... it's about 50 times better than last time.
（笑）
(Laughter)
前回のやつは
The last one...
やっぱね、チキンライスがあんま美味しくなかったんだな。
The chicken rice wasn't very good, you know?
美味しかったけど
It was good, but...
美味しかったけど、やっぱチキンライスの肉がでかすぎて、
It was good, but the meat in the chicken rice was too big,
ちょっと混ざらなかったし、
so it didn't mix well,
あとケチャップの投入タイミングもあれだったから、
and the timing for adding ketchup was off,
なんか、なんかなあって思いながら食べたのよ。
so I ate it thinking, "This is a bit off..."
で、卵3個使ってるから
And, I used three eggs, so...
んんん。
Mmm.
卵もね、濃厚で、
The egg is also rich,
分厚くて、存在感があって、
thick, has a strong presence,
美味しい。
and is delicious.
ん！
Mmm!
あ、ご主人様、これはね、大成功です、大成功。
Oh, Master, this is a great success, a great success.
美味しい。
It's delicious.
あとトマトピューレがね、トマトペーストがね、とても良いと思う。
And the tomato puree... the tomato paste is really good, I think.
美味しいです。
It's delicious!
ただちょっと、こよりの大好きな
But, my favorite...
あのー、ふわとろ生卵、半熟卵は、全然感じないかも。
you know, the fluffy, runny, soft-boiled egg... I can't really feel it at all.
ええ、ということで、ご主人様、ご満足いただけましたか？
So, with that, Master, are you satisfied?
いただけましたか？
Are you?
美味しく最後まで召し上がってくださいね。
Please enjoy it until the last bite.
またなんか作りたいというか、
I want to make something again, or rather,
ちょっと練習したいな。
I want to practice a bit.
練習してリベンジしたいまであるな。
I even want to practice and get my revenge.
はい。
Yes.
「ケチャップくれ」 トリュフおいしい。
"Give me ketchup." The truffle is delicious.
ケチャップ中に入ってるから。そう。
The ketchup is inside. Yes.
このケチャップライスにね、入ってるんで、いらないです、もう。マヨネーズで行きます。
It's in the ketchup rice, so I don't need it. I'll go with mayonnaise.
ていうことで、ねえ、今日は見てくれてありがとうございました。
Anyway, thank you for watching today.
この後ね、22時からシャドバやるんですけど、そちらも遊びに来てください。
I'll be playing Shadowverse at 10 PM, so please come and hang out there too.
つーって切ってふわってなるオムライスIHで初挑戦
My first attempt at a fluffy omelet on an IH stove
ポロポロ…ポロポロオムライスだな。
It's so crumbly... A crumbly omelet.
ふわとろは難しいぜ！
Fluffy and melty is so hard!
チャンネル登録高評価ぽちよろしくね、
Please subscribe and like the video,
ご主人様。
master.
とほほ…
*Sob sob...*
Thank you for watching!
見てくれてありがとう
Thanks for watching.
Subscribe to my channel
Click The Like button♡
Follow me on Twitter
@HakuiKoyori
See you
next time!
また会いに来てね
Come see me again, okay?
博衣こより
Hakui Koyori